<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>George Kenison</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/</link><atom:link href="https://georgekenison.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>George Kenison</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://georgekenison.github.io/media/icon_hu77e73f7cff5c696fd30270c2c33dd3bf_36783_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>George Kenison</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/</link></image><item><title>From Polynomial Invariants to Linear Loops</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2023-loop/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2023-loop/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Applications of transcendental number theory to decision problems for hypergeometric sequences</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2022-hypergeometric/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2022-hypergeometric/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Solving Invariant Generation for Unsolvable Loops</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/amrollahi-2022-invariant/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/amrollahi-2022-invariant/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Dynamical Systems and Program Analysis</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/post/dynamicaltalk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/post/dynamicaltalk/</guid><description>&lt;p>James (Ben) Worrell gave a keynote talk on algorithmic analysis of dynamical systems at the 48th ACM SIGPLAN Symposium on Principles of Programming Languages (POPL 2021).
During his talk, Ben presented some of our ongoing work on inequality decision problems for low-order holonomic sequences (&lt;a href="https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2020-positivity/">see here&lt;/a>). The abstract and recording for the talk are given below. Here are Ben&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://popl21.sigplan.org/details/POPL-2021-research-papers/69/Dynamical-Systems-and-Program-Analysis" target="_blank" rel="noopener">slides&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This talk is about the algorithmic analysis of dynamical systems and its relevance to the foundations of program analysis. A dynamical system is a state-based system that is specified by a rule specifying how the state changes over time (e.g., a swinging pendulum or a cobweb model of supply and demand in economics). While the study of dynamical systems permeates the quantitative sciences, in this talk we focus on computational aspects and their relevance to basic verification problems, such as termination and invariant synthesis. We highlight in particular certain problems that can be traced back to the program-analysis literature, e.g., concerning the decidability of termination for linear constraint loops and the computability of polyhedral and polynomial invariants for various classes of transition systems. In the talk we give some of the mathematical context of these problems, discuss recent progress, and highlight unsolved cases. The characteristic feature of the problems we consider is that they turn out to be much more challenging than they might first appear to the innocent-minded and in some cases have connections to problems at the frontiers of modern mathematics.&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9kUlHlvfU94" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>On the Skolem Problem for Reversible Sequences</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2022-reversible/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2022-reversible/</guid><description/></item><item><title>On minimality and positivity for second-order holonomic sequences</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/post/mfcstalk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/post/mfcstalk/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://georgekenison.github.io/files/202108MFCS.pdf" target="_blank">Slides&lt;/a>
on minimality and positivity for second-order holonomic sequences. Variations given at Mathematical Foundations of Computer Science 2021 (MFCS, Tallinn), the joint Forsyte (TU Wien) and Institute of Science &amp;amp; Technology Seminar, and the Open University Dynamical Systems Seminar.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>An infinite sequence $\langle u_n \rangle$ of real numbers is holonomic if it satisfies a linear recurrence relation with polynomial coefficients. Such a sequence is positive if each $u_n \geq 0$, and minimal if, given any other linearly independent sequence $\langle v_n \rangle$ satisfying the same recurrence relation, the ratio $u_n/v_n$ converges to $0$ as $n$ tends to infinity.
In recent work, the speaker and collaborators establish a Turing reduction of the problem of deciding positivity of second-order holonomic sequences to that of deciding minimality of such sequences. More specifically, we give a procedure for determining positivity of second-order holonomic sequences that terminates in all but an exceptional number of cases, and we show that in these exceptional cases positivity can be determined using an oracle for deciding minimality.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On Positivity and Minimality for Second-Order Holonomic Sequences</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2021-minimality/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2021-minimality/</guid><description/></item><item><title>On Inequality Decision Problems for Low-Order Holonomic Sequences</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2020-positivity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2020-positivity/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Holonomic techniques, periods, and decision problems</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/post/holonomictalk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/post/holonomictalk/</guid><description>&lt;p>Joël Ouaknine gave an invited talk on holonomic techniques, periods, and decision problems at Foundations of Software Technology and Theoretical Computer Science conference (FSTTCS 2020). During his talk Joël presented some of our ongoing work on inequality decision problems for low-order holonomic sequences (&lt;a href="https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2020-positivity/">see here&lt;/a>). The abstract and recording for the talk are given below.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Holonomic techniques have deep roots going back to Wallis, Euler, and Gauss, and have evolved in modern times as an important subfield of computer algebra, thanks in large part to the work of Zeilberger and others over the past three decades. In this talk, I will give an overview of the area, and in particular will present a select survey of known and original results on decision problems for holonomic sequences and functions. I will also discuss some surprising connections to the theory of periods and exponential periods, which are classical objects of study in algebraic geometry and number theory; in particular, I will relate the decidability of certain decision problems for holonomic sequences to deep conjectures about periods and exponential periods, notably those due to Kontsevich and Zagier.&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/01j0OtQRjNk" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Principles of design and learning mathematics</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/post/designeveryday/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/post/designeveryday/</guid><description>&lt;p>In his book, The Design of Everyday Things, Norman argues that a skilled practitioner or expert minimises the cognitive burden of performing tasks by automating subroutines and processes.
Thus the expert need only engage consciously with the minutiae and subtleties of the task at hand.
The author includes the following insight by philosopher and mathematician Alfred North Whitehead:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It is a profoundly erroneous truism, repeated by all copy-books and by eminent people when they are making speeches, that we should cultivate the habit of thinking of what we are doing. The precise opposite is the case. Civilization advances by extending the number of important operations which we can perform without thinking about them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(Alfred North Whitehead, 1911)&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It is interesting to link Whitehead&amp;rsquo;s observation to schools of thought in mathematics education; that is, the academic study of didactical practice and learning outcomes in mathematics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Casual observation and anecdotal evidence suggest that the topic of effective learning in mathematics appears to be of little concern to many lecturers. Freudenthal offers the following observation: complete mastery of a topic separates some teachers from their learners.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I have observed, not only with other people but also with myself. . . that sources of
insight can be clogged by automatisms. One finally masters an activity so perfectly
that the question of how and why [students have difficultly with these procedures]
is not asked any more, cannot be asked any more, and is not even understood any
more as a meaningful and relevant question.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(Freudenthal)&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>There are many theories on how learners internalise and assimilate new mathematical concepts.
We may relate Freudenthal&amp;rsquo;s automatisms to encapsulation, a term frequently used to indicate
cognitive development. There are several theories in the literature that frame encapsulation
from a constructivist epistemology of learning, these include: Dubinsky&amp;rsquo;s reactive abstraction for advanced mathematical thinking; APOS theory (Action, Process, Object, Schema) in Cottrill et al.; Sfard&amp;rsquo;s dual theory with its focus on rei fication; and Gray and Tall&amp;rsquo;s
procepts (symbols may act as both processes and concepts in learners&amp;rsquo; schemata).
There are significant differences between these theories. For instance APOS theory and Sfard&amp;rsquo;s
theory suggest that cognitive development of a learner&amp;rsquo;s schema is somewhat linear: Cottrill et
al. believe learners encounter the stages Action, Process, Object, Schema in order; whilst Sfard
identifies three separate stages interiorization, condensation and reifi cation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is interesting to question further the implications of good design (importing good practice from engineering and production) on teaching in higher education. The interface blending research, teaching, and learning has much to offer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On the Skolem Problem and prime powers</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2020-skolem/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2020-skolem/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Markov Reachability for biased cycles</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/post/fourcycle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/post/fourcycle/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-markov-reachability-problem">The Markov Reachability Problem&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We are interested in decision problems for Markov chains and in particular, the &lt;em>Markov Reachability Problem&lt;/em>. Given a stochastic matrix $K\in\mathbb{Q}^{d\times d}$ and positive $r\in\mathbb{Q}$, determine whether there exist an $n\in\mathbb{N}$ such that $K^n(1,2)=r$.
That is to say, does there exist an $n\in\mathbb{N}$ such that the probability of travelling from state $1$ to state $2$ is exactly $r$.
The decidability of the Markov Reachability Problem is currently open.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We note the Markov Reachability Problem is more difficult than the process of determining whether there is a path of length $n$ originating at state $1$ and terminating at state $2$ with associated probability $r$.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="cycle-graphs">Cycle graphs&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We shall consider the Markov Reachability Problem for a toy example.
Let us define the entries of an $m\times m$ stochastic matrix $K$ with rows and columns indexed by the states ${1,2,\ldots, m}$ as follows&lt;/p>
&lt;p>\begin{equation*}
K(i,j) = \begin{cases}
p &amp;amp; \text{if } j=i+1 \pmod{m},\\
1-p &amp;amp; \text{if } j=i-1 \pmod{m},\\
0 &amp;amp; \text{otherwise}.
\end{cases}
\end{equation*}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Markov chain associated to $K$ is a directed graph with states ${1,2,\ldots, m}$ so that at each timestep the transitions $\ell\mapsto\ell+1\pmod{m}$ and $\ell\mapsto\ell-1\pmod{m}$ occur with probabilities $p$ and $1-p$, respectively.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We call the Markov chain associated to $K$ an &lt;em>$m$-cycle&lt;/em> and, in addition, if $p\neq 1/2$ we call the Markov chain a &lt;em>biased $m$-cycle&lt;/em>. Without loss of generality, we shall assume throughout that $p\in(0,1/2)$.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-biased-4-cycle">The biased $4$-cycle&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Consider the decidability of the Markov Reachability Problem for the biased $4$-cycle. It is clear that the only value of $r\in\mathbb{Q}$ that is not covered by stochastic asymptotic considerations is $r={1}/{2}$.
We prove the following.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Proposition:&lt;/strong>
Let $K$ be the stochastic transition matrix
\begin{equation*}
K := \begin{pmatrix}
0 &amp;amp; p &amp;amp; 0 &amp;amp; 1-p\\ 1-p &amp;amp; 0 &amp;amp; p &amp;amp; 0\\ 0 &amp;amp; 1-p &amp;amp; 0 &amp;amp; p\\ p &amp;amp; 0 &amp;amp; 1-p &amp;amp; 0
\end{pmatrix}
\end{equation*}
for the biased $4$-cycle with $p\in(0,1/2)$. There is no $m\in\mathbb{N}$ for which $K^m(1,2) = 1/2$.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Proof.&lt;/strong> Observe that a path originating at state $1$ and terminating at state $2$ on the $4$-cycle graph has odd length.
We can categorise such paths by the number of state transitions $\ell\mapsto\ell+1\pmod{4}$ and $\ell\mapsto\ell-1\pmod{4}$ made.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Given that $K^{2m}(1,2)=0$ for each $m\in\mathbb{N}$. We need only consider two cases: paths with length $4m+1$ and those with length $4m+3$. We can write the entries $K^{4m+1}(1,2)$ and $K^{4m+3}(1,2)$ in terms of sums of odd binomial coefficients such that
\begin{align*}
K^{4m+1}(1,2) &amp;amp;= \sum_{j=0}^{2m} \binom{4m+1}{2j+1} p^{2j+1}(1-p)^{4m-2j}, \text{ and }\\&lt;br>
K^{4m+3}(1,2) &amp;amp;= \sum_{j=0}^{2m} \binom{4m+3}{2j+2} p^{2j+2}(1-p)^{4m-2j+1}.
\end{align*}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Using standard techniques for binomial expansions we can express $K^{4n+1}(1,2)$ as follows
\begin{align*}
1- (1-2p)^{4m+1} &amp;amp;= (p + (1-p))^{4m+1} -(-p+(1-p))^{4m+1} \\
&amp;amp;= \sum_{j=0}^{4m+1} \binom{4m+1}{j} p^j (1-p)^{4m+1-j} (1-(-1)^j) \\
&amp;amp;= 2\sum_{j=0}^{2m} \binom{4m+1}{2j+1} p^{2j+1} (1-p)^{4m-2j} \\
&amp;amp;= 2K^{4m+1}(1,2).
\end{align*}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Suppose, for a contradiction, that there is an $m\equiv 1 \pmod{4}$ for which $K^m(1,2)={1}/{2}$. Then $0 = K^m(1,2) - {1}/{2} = -(2p-1)^{m}/2$, but this contradicts our assumption that $p\in(0,1/{2})$. The fact that there is no $m\equiv 3 \pmod{4}$ for which $K^m(1,2) = 1/{2}$ follows by a similar argument. Thus we determine there is no $m\in\mathbb{N}$ for which $K^m(1,2)=1/{2}$ as required.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The decidability of the Markov Reachability Problem for the fair $4$-cycle is trivial. In fact, the problem is decidable for the general $m$-cycle.
It can be shown that the Markov Reachability Problem is decidable for biased cycles with $m$ states, but that is a post for another time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Slides</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/slides/example/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/slides/example/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="create-slides-in-markdown-with-wowchemy">Create slides in Markdown with Wowchemy&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://wowchemy.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Wowchemy&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="https://wowchemy.com/docs/content/slides/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Documentation&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="features">Features&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Efficiently write slides in Markdown&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3-in-1: Create, Present, and Publish your slides&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Supports speaker notes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mobile friendly slides&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="controls">Controls&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Next: &lt;code>Right Arrow&lt;/code> or &lt;code>Space&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Previous: &lt;code>Left Arrow&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Start: &lt;code>Home&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Finish: &lt;code>End&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Overview: &lt;code>Esc&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Speaker notes: &lt;code>S&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fullscreen: &lt;code>F&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Zoom: &lt;code>Alt + Click&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://revealjs.com/pdf-export/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PDF Export&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="code-highlighting">Code Highlighting&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Inline code: &lt;code>variable&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Code block:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-python" data-lang="python">&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="n">porridge&lt;/span> &lt;span class="o">=&lt;/span> &lt;span class="s2">&amp;#34;blueberry&amp;#34;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="k">if&lt;/span> &lt;span class="n">porridge&lt;/span> &lt;span class="o">==&lt;/span> &lt;span class="s2">&amp;#34;blueberry&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">:&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl"> &lt;span class="nb">print&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">(&lt;/span>&lt;span class="s2">&amp;#34;Eating...&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">)&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="math">Math&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In-line math: $x + y = z$&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Block math:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>$$
f\left( x \right) = ;\frac{{2\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x - 4} \right)}}{{\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x + 1} \right)}}
$$&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="fragments">Fragments&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Make content appear incrementally&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">{{% fragment %}} One {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">{{% fragment %}} **Two** {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">{{% fragment %}} Three {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Press &lt;code>Space&lt;/code> to play!&lt;/p>
&lt;span class="fragment " >
One
&lt;/span>
&lt;span class="fragment " >
&lt;strong>Two&lt;/strong>
&lt;/span>
&lt;span class="fragment " >
Three
&lt;/span>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>A fragment can accept two optional parameters:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;code>class&lt;/code>: use a custom style (requires definition in custom CSS)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>weight&lt;/code>: sets the order in which a fragment appears&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="speaker-notes">Speaker Notes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Add speaker notes to your presentation&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-markdown" data-lang="markdown">&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">{{% speaker_note %}}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="k">-&lt;/span> Only the speaker can read these notes
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="k">-&lt;/span> Press &lt;span class="sb">`S`&lt;/span> key to view
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl"> {{% /speaker_note %}}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Press the &lt;code>S&lt;/code> key to view the speaker notes!&lt;/p>
&lt;aside class="notes">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Only the speaker can read these notes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Press &lt;code>S&lt;/code> key to view&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/aside>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="themes">Themes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>black: Black background, white text, blue links (default)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>white: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li>
&lt;li>league: Gray background, white text, blue links&lt;/li>
&lt;li>beige: Beige background, dark text, brown links&lt;/li>
&lt;li>sky: Blue background, thin dark text, blue links&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>night: Black background, thick white text, orange links&lt;/li>
&lt;li>serif: Cappuccino background, gray text, brown links&lt;/li>
&lt;li>simple: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li>
&lt;li>solarized: Cream-colored background, dark green text, blue links&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;section data-noprocess data-shortcode-slide
data-background-image="/media/boards.jpg"
>
&lt;h2 id="custom-slide">Custom Slide&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Customize the slide style and background&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-markdown" data-lang="markdown">&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">{{&lt;span class="p">&amp;lt;&lt;/span> &lt;span class="nt">slide&lt;/span> &lt;span class="na">background-image&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">=&lt;/span>&lt;span class="s">&amp;#34;/media/boards.jpg&amp;#34;&lt;/span> &lt;span class="p">&amp;gt;&lt;/span>}}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">{{&lt;span class="p">&amp;lt;&lt;/span> &lt;span class="nt">slide&lt;/span> &lt;span class="na">background-color&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">=&lt;/span>&lt;span class="s">&amp;#34;#0000FF&amp;#34;&lt;/span> &lt;span class="p">&amp;gt;&lt;/span>}}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">{{&lt;span class="p">&amp;lt;&lt;/span> &lt;span class="nt">slide&lt;/span> &lt;span class="na">class&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">=&lt;/span>&lt;span class="s">&amp;#34;my-style&amp;#34;&lt;/span> &lt;span class="p">&amp;gt;&lt;/span>}}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="custom-css-example">Custom CSS Example&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s make headers navy colored.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Create &lt;code>assets/css/reveal_custom.css&lt;/code> with:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-css" data-lang="css">&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="p">.&lt;/span>&lt;span class="nc">reveal&lt;/span> &lt;span class="nt">section&lt;/span> &lt;span class="nt">h1&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">,&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="p">.&lt;/span>&lt;span class="nc">reveal&lt;/span> &lt;span class="nt">section&lt;/span> &lt;span class="nt">h2&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">,&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="p">.&lt;/span>&lt;span class="nc">reveal&lt;/span> &lt;span class="nt">section&lt;/span> &lt;span class="nt">h3&lt;/span> &lt;span class="p">{&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl"> &lt;span class="k">color&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">:&lt;/span> &lt;span class="kc">navy&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="p">}&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="questions">Questions?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://discord.gg/z8wNYzb" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ask&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://wowchemy.com/docs/content/slides/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Documentation&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Statistics in conjugacy classes in free groups</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2019-statistics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2019-statistics/</guid><description/></item><item><title>WORReLL'23</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/worrell/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/worrell/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="workshop-on-reachability-recurrences-and-loops">Workshop On Reachability, Recurrences, and Loops&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="satellite-workshop-at-icalp-2023httpsicalp2023csupbde">Satellite Workshop at &lt;a href="https://icalp2023.cs.upb.de/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ICALP 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="paderborn-germany">Paderborn, Germany&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="monday-10th-july-2023">Monday 10th July 2023&lt;/h4>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="topic">Topic&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Recursively defined sequences are foundational objects of study in the computational sciences; they arise naturally in areas such as: the analysis of algorithms, weighted automata, loop termination, and probabilistic models.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="aim">Aim&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The aim of WORReLL'23 is to bring together researchers from the community and showcase cutting-edge research on the above topics.
The one-day workshop will also celebrate the research contributions of Professor James Worrell (also known as Ben). For context, Ben is giving an &lt;a href="https://icalp2023.cs.upb.de/invited-speakers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">invited talk&lt;/a> at ICALP this year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Coincidentally, the workshop is a few days prior to Ben&amp;rsquo;s birthday.
We are also planning to organise a birthday dinner as the closing event of the workshop, so please take this into consideration for planning your travel to Paderborn.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="hahahugoshortcodes0hbhb">
&lt;figure id="figure-professor-james-worrell">
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="Professor James Worrell" srcset="
/worrell/jbw_huf8e734c4952d304039a82f5706908e3d_19221_eada5ef6542e535558aa56cf078fc0f0.webp 400w,
/worrell/jbw_huf8e734c4952d304039a82f5706908e3d_19221_1c631d07bcd7f5cf20a3ad34cdc28ff3.webp 760w,
/worrell/jbw_huf8e734c4952d304039a82f5706908e3d_19221_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w"
src="https://georgekenison.github.io/worrell/jbw_huf8e734c4952d304039a82f5706908e3d_19221_eada5ef6542e535558aa56cf078fc0f0.webp"
width="310"
height="310"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;figcaption>
Professor James Worrell
&lt;/figcaption>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="confirmed-speakers">Confirmed Speakers&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://pcbell.github.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Paul Bell&lt;/a> (Keele)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.irif.fr/~berthe/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Valérie Berthé&lt;/a> (CNRS, Paris)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.wits.ac.za/staff/academic-a-z-listing/l/florianlucawitsacza/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Florian Luca&lt;/a> (Witwatersrand)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://people.mpi-sws.org/~joel/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Joël Ouaknine&lt;/a> (MPI-SWS)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cgi.csc.liv.ac.uk/~igor/Igor_Potapovs_Home_Page/Home.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Igor Potapov&lt;/a> (Liverpool)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="schedule">Schedule&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To be announced&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="organisers">Organisers&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://georgekenison.github.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">George Kenison&lt;/a> (TU Wien)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.irif.fr/~mahsa/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mahsa Shirmohammadi&lt;/a> (CNRS, Paris)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Orbit counting in conjugacy classes for free groups acting on trees</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2015-orbit/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2015-orbit/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/admin/config.yml</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/admin/config.yml</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>