<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>George Kenison</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/</link><atom:link href="https://georgekenison.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>George Kenison</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://georgekenison.github.io/media/icon_hu77e73f7cff5c696fd30270c2c33dd3bf_36783_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>George Kenison</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/</link></image><item><title>(Un)Solvable Loop Analysis</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/amrollahi-2023-unsolvable/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/amrollahi-2023-unsolvable/</guid><description>&lt;p>Extended version of the conference paper &lt;em>Solving Invariant Generation for Unsolvable Loops&lt;/em> published at SAS 2022 (&lt;a href="https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/amrollahi-2022-invariant/">see here&lt;/a>).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Summer Workshops (2023)</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/post/2023workshops/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/post/2023workshops/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am co-organising two workshops in July 2023: WORReLL'23 (&lt;a href="https://georgekenison.github.io/worrell/">see here&lt;/a>) and Autobóz 2023 (&lt;a href="https://autoboz.org/home-23" target="_blank" rel="noopener">see here&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="worrell23">WORReLL'23&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>WORRELL'23 is a one-day satellite workshop at ICALP'23.
The aim of the workshop is to bring together researchers from the community and showcase cutting-edge research on &lt;em>Reachability&lt;/em>, &lt;em>Recurrences&lt;/em>, and &lt;em>Loops&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To participate in-person, please register for WORReLL'23 through ICALP&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://icalp2023.cs.upb.de/registration/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">registration portal&lt;/a>. To participate remotely over Zoom, please contact me for further details.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet">&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr">&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ICALP2023?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#ICALP2023&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Workshops?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Workshops&lt;/a> | July 10th &lt;br>Workshop On Reachability, Recurrences, and Loops &amp;#39;23 (WORReLL&amp;#39;23)&lt;br>👉Organizers:&lt;br>&amp;gt; George Kenison &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tu_wien?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@tu_wien&lt;/a>&lt;br>&amp;gt; Mahsa Shirmohammadi &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/IRIF_Paris?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@IRIF_Paris&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/univ_paris_cite?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@univ_paris_cite&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/INS2I_CNRS?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@INS2I_CNRS&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://t.co/tUhXQccIYu">pic.twitter.com/tUhXQccIYu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&amp;mdash; ICALP 2023 (@ICALPconf) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ICALPconf/status/1639282442539266052?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 24, 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/blockquote> &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8">&lt;/script>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="autobóz">Autobóz&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Autobóz is a yearly week-long invitational research camp on Logic, Automata, and
Games.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In 2023, Autobóz will take place at the Seminarhaus in the Hessische Staatsdomäne Frankenhausen the week between &lt;a href="https://icalp2023.cs.upb.de/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ICALP&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://highlights-conference.org/2023/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Highlights&lt;/a>. Indeed, Autobóz is excited to partnership with Highlights as part of the &lt;a href="https://highlights-conference.org/2023/hcrw" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Highlights Collaborative Research Week&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have solicited expert tutorials on topics as diverse as: &lt;em>Circuit Verification using Computer Algebra&lt;/em>, &lt;em>Decision Problems for Subclasses of Rational Relations&lt;/em>, and &lt;em>Weak Memory Models in Concurrency&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Solving Invariant Generation for Unsolvable Loops</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/post/2022sastalk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/post/2022sastalk/</guid><description>&lt;p>Marcel Moosbrugger presented our joint work (&lt;a href="https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/amrollahi-2022-invariant/">see here&lt;/a>)
on invariant generation for unsolvable loops at the ACM SIGPLAN 29th Static Analysis Symposium (SAS 2022).&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Automatically generating invariants, key to computer-aided analysis of probabilistic and deterministic programs and compiler optimisation, is a challenging open problem. Whilst the problem is in general undecidable, the goal is settled for restricted classes of loops. For the class of solvable loops, introduced by Kapur and Rodríguez-Carbonell in 2004, one can automatically compute invariants from closed-form solutions of recurrence equations that model the loop behaviour. In this paper we establish a technique for invariant synthesis for loops that are not solvable, termed unsolvable loops. Our approach automatically partitions the program variables and identifies the so-called defective variables that characterise unsolvability. We further present a novel technique that automatically synthesises polynomials, in the defective variables, that admit closed-form solutions and thus lead to polynomial loop invariants. Our implementation and experiments demonstrate both the feasibility and applicability of our approach to both deterministic and probabilistic programs.&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fZbGGx2ifho" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Positivity Problems for Reversible Linear Recurrence Sequences</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2023-reversiblepositivity/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2023-reversiblepositivity/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Membership Problem for Hypergeometric Sequences with Quadratic Parameters</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2023-hypergeometric/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2023-hypergeometric/</guid><description/></item><item><title>From Polynomial Invariants to Linear Loops</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2023-loop/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2023-loop/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Membership and Threshold Problems for Hypergeometric Sequences with Quadratic Parameters</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2022-hypergeometric/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2022-hypergeometric/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Solving Invariant Generation for Unsolvable Loops</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/amrollahi-2022-invariant/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/amrollahi-2022-invariant/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Dynamical Systems and Program Analysis</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/post/dynamicaltalk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/post/dynamicaltalk/</guid><description>&lt;p>James (Ben) Worrell gave a keynote talk on algorithmic analysis of dynamical systems at the 48th ACM SIGPLAN Symposium on Principles of Programming Languages (POPL 2021).
During his talk, Ben presented some of our ongoing work on inequality decision problems for low-order holonomic sequences (&lt;a href="https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2020-positivity/">see here&lt;/a>). The abstract and recording for the talk are given below. Here are Ben&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://popl21.sigplan.org/details/POPL-2021-research-papers/69/Dynamical-Systems-and-Program-Analysis" target="_blank" rel="noopener">slides&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This talk is about the algorithmic analysis of dynamical systems and its relevance to the foundations of program analysis. A dynamical system is a state-based system that is specified by a rule specifying how the state changes over time (e.g., a swinging pendulum or a cobweb model of supply and demand in economics). While the study of dynamical systems permeates the quantitative sciences, in this talk we focus on computational aspects and their relevance to basic verification problems, such as termination and invariant synthesis. We highlight in particular certain problems that can be traced back to the program-analysis literature, e.g., concerning the decidability of termination for linear constraint loops and the computability of polyhedral and polynomial invariants for various classes of transition systems. In the talk we give some of the mathematical context of these problems, discuss recent progress, and highlight unsolved cases. The characteristic feature of the problems we consider is that they turn out to be much more challenging than they might first appear to the innocent-minded and in some cases have connections to problems at the frontiers of modern mathematics.&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9kUlHlvfU94" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>On the Skolem Problem for Reversible Sequences</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2022-reversible/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2022-reversible/</guid><description/></item><item><title>On minimality and positivity for second-order holonomic sequences</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/post/mfcstalk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/post/mfcstalk/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://georgekenison.github.io/files/202108MFCS.pdf" target="_blank">Slides&lt;/a>
on minimality and positivity for second-order holonomic sequences. Variations given at Mathematical Foundations of Computer Science 2021 (MFCS, Tallinn), the joint Forsyte (TU Wien) and Institute of Science &amp;amp; Technology Seminar, and the Open University Dynamical Systems Seminar.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>An infinite sequence $\langle u_n \rangle$ of real numbers is holonomic if it satisfies a linear recurrence relation with polynomial coefficients. Such a sequence is positive if each $u_n \geq 0$, and minimal if, given any other linearly independent sequence $\langle v_n \rangle$ satisfying the same recurrence relation, the ratio $u_n/v_n$ converges to $0$ as $n$ tends to infinity.
In recent work, the speaker and collaborators establish a Turing reduction of the problem of deciding positivity of second-order holonomic sequences to that of deciding minimality of such sequences. More specifically, we give a procedure for determining positivity of second-order holonomic sequences that terminates in all but an exceptional number of cases, and we show that in these exceptional cases positivity can be determined using an oracle for deciding minimality.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On Positivity and Minimality for Second-Order Holonomic Sequences</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2021-minimality/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2021-minimality/</guid><description/></item><item><title>On Inequality Decision Problems for Low-Order Holonomic Sequences</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2020-positivity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2020-positivity/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Holonomic techniques, periods, and decision problems</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/post/holonomictalk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/post/holonomictalk/</guid><description>&lt;p>Joël Ouaknine gave an invited talk on holonomic techniques, periods, and decision problems at Foundations of Software Technology and Theoretical Computer Science conference (FSTTCS 2020). During his talk Joël presented some of our ongoing work on inequality decision problems for low-order holonomic sequences (&lt;a href="https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2020-positivity/">see here&lt;/a>). The abstract and recording for the talk are given below.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Holonomic techniques have deep roots going back to Wallis, Euler, and Gauss, and have evolved in modern times as an important subfield of computer algebra, thanks in large part to the work of Zeilberger and others over the past three decades. In this talk, I will give an overview of the area, and in particular will present a select survey of known and original results on decision problems for holonomic sequences and functions. I will also discuss some surprising connections to the theory of periods and exponential periods, which are classical objects of study in algebraic geometry and number theory; in particular, I will relate the decidability of certain decision problems for holonomic sequences to deep conjectures about periods and exponential periods, notably those due to Kontsevich and Zagier.&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/01j0OtQRjNk" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Principles of design and learning mathematics</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/post/designeveryday/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/post/designeveryday/</guid><description>&lt;p>In his book, The Design of Everyday Things, Norman argues that a skilled practitioner or expert minimises the cognitive burden of performing tasks by automating subroutines and processes.
Thus the expert need only engage consciously with the minutiae and subtleties of the task at hand.
The author includes the following insight by philosopher and mathematician Alfred North Whitehead:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It is a profoundly erroneous truism, repeated by all copy-books and by eminent people when they are making speeches, that we should cultivate the habit of thinking of what we are doing. The precise opposite is the case. Civilization advances by extending the number of important operations which we can perform without thinking about them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(Alfred North Whitehead, 1911)&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It is interesting to link Whitehead&amp;rsquo;s observation to schools of thought in mathematics education; that is, the academic study of didactical practice and learning outcomes in mathematics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Casual observation and anecdotal evidence suggest that the topic of effective learning in mathematics appears to be of little concern to many lecturers. Freudenthal offers the following observation: complete mastery of a topic separates some teachers from their learners.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I have observed, not only with other people but also with myself. . . that sources of
insight can be clogged by automatisms. One finally masters an activity so perfectly
that the question of how and why [students have difficultly with these procedures]
is not asked any more, cannot be asked any more, and is not even understood any
more as a meaningful and relevant question.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(Freudenthal)&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>There are many theories on how learners internalise and assimilate new mathematical concepts.
We may relate Freudenthal&amp;rsquo;s automatisms to encapsulation, a term frequently used to indicate
cognitive development. There are several theories in the literature that frame encapsulation
from a constructivist epistemology of learning, these include: Dubinsky&amp;rsquo;s reactive abstraction for advanced mathematical thinking; APOS theory (Action, Process, Object, Schema) in Cottrill et al.; Sfard&amp;rsquo;s dual theory with its focus on rei fication; and Gray and Tall&amp;rsquo;s
procepts (symbols may act as both processes and concepts in learners&amp;rsquo; schemata).
There are significant differences between these theories. For instance APOS theory and Sfard&amp;rsquo;s
theory suggest that cognitive development of a learner&amp;rsquo;s schema is somewhat linear: Cottrill et
al. believe learners encounter the stages Action, Process, Object, Schema in order; whilst Sfard
identifies three separate stages interiorization, condensation and reifi cation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is interesting to question further the implications of good design (importing good practice from engineering and production) on teaching in higher education. The interface blending research, teaching, and learning has much to offer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On the Skolem Problem and prime powers</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2020-skolem/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2020-skolem/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Markov Reachability for biased cycles</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/post/fourcycle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/post/fourcycle/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-markov-reachability-problem">The Markov Reachability Problem&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We are interested in decision problems for Markov chains and in particular, the &lt;em>Markov Reachability Problem&lt;/em>. Given a stochastic matrix $K\in\mathbb{Q}^{d\times d}$ and positive $r\in\mathbb{Q}$, determine whether there exist an $n\in\mathbb{N}$ such that $K^n(1,2)=r$.
That is to say, does there exist an $n\in\mathbb{N}$ such that the probability of travelling from state $1$ to state $2$ is exactly $r$.
The decidability of the Markov Reachability Problem is currently open.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We note the Markov Reachability Problem is more difficult than the process of determining whether there is a path of length $n$ originating at state $1$ and terminating at state $2$ with associated probability $r$.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="cycle-graphs">Cycle graphs&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We shall consider the Markov Reachability Problem for a toy example.
Let us define the entries of an $m\times m$ stochastic matrix $K$ with rows and columns indexed by the states ${1,2,\ldots, m}$ as follows&lt;/p>
&lt;p>\begin{equation*}
K(i,j) = \begin{cases}
p &amp;amp; \text{if } j=i+1 \pmod{m},\\
1-p &amp;amp; \text{if } j=i-1 \pmod{m},\\
0 &amp;amp; \text{otherwise}.
\end{cases}
\end{equation*}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Markov chain associated to $K$ is a directed graph with states ${1,2,\ldots, m}$ so that at each timestep the transitions $\ell\mapsto\ell+1\pmod{m}$ and $\ell\mapsto\ell-1\pmod{m}$ occur with probabilities $p$ and $1-p$, respectively.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We call the Markov chain associated to $K$ an &lt;em>$m$-cycle&lt;/em> and, in addition, if $p\neq 1/2$ we call the Markov chain a &lt;em>biased $m$-cycle&lt;/em>. Without loss of generality, we shall assume throughout that $p\in(0,1/2)$.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-biased-4-cycle">The biased $4$-cycle&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Consider the decidability of the Markov Reachability Problem for the biased $4$-cycle. It is clear that the only value of $r\in\mathbb{Q}$ that is not covered by stochastic asymptotic considerations is $r={1}/{2}$.
We prove the following.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Proposition:&lt;/strong>
Let $K$ be the stochastic transition matrix
\begin{equation*}
K := \begin{pmatrix}
0 &amp;amp; p &amp;amp; 0 &amp;amp; 1-p\\ 1-p &amp;amp; 0 &amp;amp; p &amp;amp; 0\\ 0 &amp;amp; 1-p &amp;amp; 0 &amp;amp; p\\ p &amp;amp; 0 &amp;amp; 1-p &amp;amp; 0
\end{pmatrix}
\end{equation*}
for the biased $4$-cycle with $p\in(0,1/2)$. There is no $m\in\mathbb{N}$ for which $K^m(1,2) = 1/2$.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Proof.&lt;/strong> Observe that a path originating at state $1$ and terminating at state $2$ on the $4$-cycle graph has odd length.
We can categorise such paths by the number of state transitions $\ell\mapsto\ell+1\pmod{4}$ and $\ell\mapsto\ell-1\pmod{4}$ made.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Given that $K^{2m}(1,2)=0$ for each $m\in\mathbb{N}$. We need only consider two cases: paths with length $4m+1$ and those with length $4m+3$. We can write the entries $K^{4m+1}(1,2)$ and $K^{4m+3}(1,2)$ in terms of sums of odd binomial coefficients such that
\begin{align*}
K^{4m+1}(1,2) &amp;amp;= \sum_{j=0}^{2m} \binom{4m+1}{2j+1} p^{2j+1}(1-p)^{4m-2j}, \text{ and }\\&lt;br>
K^{4m+3}(1,2) &amp;amp;= \sum_{j=0}^{2m} \binom{4m+3}{2j+2} p^{2j+2}(1-p)^{4m-2j+1}.
\end{align*}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Using standard techniques for binomial expansions we can express $K^{4n+1}(1,2)$ as follows
\begin{align*}
1- (1-2p)^{4m+1} &amp;amp;= (p + (1-p))^{4m+1} -(-p+(1-p))^{4m+1} \\
&amp;amp;= \sum_{j=0}^{4m+1} \binom{4m+1}{j} p^j (1-p)^{4m+1-j} (1-(-1)^j) \\
&amp;amp;= 2\sum_{j=0}^{2m} \binom{4m+1}{2j+1} p^{2j+1} (1-p)^{4m-2j} \\
&amp;amp;= 2K^{4m+1}(1,2).
\end{align*}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Suppose, for a contradiction, that there is an $m\equiv 1 \pmod{4}$ for which $K^m(1,2)={1}/{2}$. Then $0 = K^m(1,2) - {1}/{2} = -(2p-1)^{m}/2$, but this contradicts our assumption that $p\in(0,1/{2})$. The fact that there is no $m\equiv 3 \pmod{4}$ for which $K^m(1,2) = 1/{2}$ follows by a similar argument. Thus we determine there is no $m\in\mathbb{N}$ for which $K^m(1,2)=1/{2}$ as required.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The decidability of the Markov Reachability Problem for the fair $4$-cycle is trivial. In fact, the problem is decidable for the general $m$-cycle.
It can be shown that the Markov Reachability Problem is decidable for biased cycles with $m$ states, but that is a post for another time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Slides</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/slides/example/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/slides/example/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="create-slides-in-markdown-with-wowchemy">Create slides in Markdown with Wowchemy&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://wowchemy.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Wowchemy&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="https://wowchemy.com/docs/content/slides/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Documentation&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="features">Features&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Efficiently write slides in Markdown&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3-in-1: Create, Present, and Publish your slides&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Supports speaker notes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mobile friendly slides&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="controls">Controls&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Next: &lt;code>Right Arrow&lt;/code> or &lt;code>Space&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Previous: &lt;code>Left Arrow&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Start: &lt;code>Home&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Finish: &lt;code>End&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Overview: &lt;code>Esc&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Speaker notes: &lt;code>S&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fullscreen: &lt;code>F&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Zoom: &lt;code>Alt + Click&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://revealjs.com/pdf-export/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PDF Export&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="code-highlighting">Code Highlighting&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Inline code: &lt;code>variable&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Code block:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-python" data-lang="python">&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="n">porridge&lt;/span> &lt;span class="o">=&lt;/span> &lt;span class="s2">&amp;#34;blueberry&amp;#34;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="k">if&lt;/span> &lt;span class="n">porridge&lt;/span> &lt;span class="o">==&lt;/span> &lt;span class="s2">&amp;#34;blueberry&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">:&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl"> &lt;span class="nb">print&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">(&lt;/span>&lt;span class="s2">&amp;#34;Eating...&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">)&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="math">Math&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In-line math: $x + y = z$&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Block math:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>$$
f\left( x \right) = ;\frac{{2\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x - 4} \right)}}{{\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x + 1} \right)}}
$$&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="fragments">Fragments&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Make content appear incrementally&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">{{% fragment %}} One {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">{{% fragment %}} **Two** {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">{{% fragment %}} Three {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Press &lt;code>Space&lt;/code> to play!&lt;/p>
&lt;span class="fragment " >
One
&lt;/span>
&lt;span class="fragment " >
&lt;strong>Two&lt;/strong>
&lt;/span>
&lt;span class="fragment " >
Three
&lt;/span>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>A fragment can accept two optional parameters:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;code>class&lt;/code>: use a custom style (requires definition in custom CSS)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>weight&lt;/code>: sets the order in which a fragment appears&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="speaker-notes">Speaker Notes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Add speaker notes to your presentation&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-markdown" data-lang="markdown">&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">{{% speaker_note %}}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="k">-&lt;/span> Only the speaker can read these notes
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="k">-&lt;/span> Press &lt;span class="sb">`S`&lt;/span> key to view
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl"> {{% /speaker_note %}}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Press the &lt;code>S&lt;/code> key to view the speaker notes!&lt;/p>
&lt;aside class="notes">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Only the speaker can read these notes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Press &lt;code>S&lt;/code> key to view&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/aside>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="themes">Themes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>black: Black background, white text, blue links (default)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>white: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li>
&lt;li>league: Gray background, white text, blue links&lt;/li>
&lt;li>beige: Beige background, dark text, brown links&lt;/li>
&lt;li>sky: Blue background, thin dark text, blue links&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>night: Black background, thick white text, orange links&lt;/li>
&lt;li>serif: Cappuccino background, gray text, brown links&lt;/li>
&lt;li>simple: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li>
&lt;li>solarized: Cream-colored background, dark green text, blue links&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;section data-noprocess data-shortcode-slide
data-background-image="/media/boards.jpg"
>
&lt;h2 id="custom-slide">Custom Slide&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Customize the slide style and background&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-markdown" data-lang="markdown">&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">{{&lt;span class="p">&amp;lt;&lt;/span> &lt;span class="nt">slide&lt;/span> &lt;span class="na">background-image&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">=&lt;/span>&lt;span class="s">&amp;#34;/media/boards.jpg&amp;#34;&lt;/span> &lt;span class="p">&amp;gt;&lt;/span>}}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">{{&lt;span class="p">&amp;lt;&lt;/span> &lt;span class="nt">slide&lt;/span> &lt;span class="na">background-color&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">=&lt;/span>&lt;span class="s">&amp;#34;#0000FF&amp;#34;&lt;/span> &lt;span class="p">&amp;gt;&lt;/span>}}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">{{&lt;span class="p">&amp;lt;&lt;/span> &lt;span class="nt">slide&lt;/span> &lt;span class="na">class&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">=&lt;/span>&lt;span class="s">&amp;#34;my-style&amp;#34;&lt;/span> &lt;span class="p">&amp;gt;&lt;/span>}}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="custom-css-example">Custom CSS Example&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s make headers navy colored.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Create &lt;code>assets/css/reveal_custom.css&lt;/code> with:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-css" data-lang="css">&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="p">.&lt;/span>&lt;span class="nc">reveal&lt;/span> &lt;span class="nt">section&lt;/span> &lt;span class="nt">h1&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">,&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="p">.&lt;/span>&lt;span class="nc">reveal&lt;/span> &lt;span class="nt">section&lt;/span> &lt;span class="nt">h2&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">,&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="p">.&lt;/span>&lt;span class="nc">reveal&lt;/span> &lt;span class="nt">section&lt;/span> &lt;span class="nt">h3&lt;/span> &lt;span class="p">{&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl"> &lt;span class="k">color&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">:&lt;/span> &lt;span class="kc">navy&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="p">}&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="questions">Questions?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://discord.gg/z8wNYzb" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ask&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://wowchemy.com/docs/content/slides/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Documentation&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Statistics in conjugacy classes in free groups</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2019-statistics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2019-statistics/</guid><description/></item><item><title>WORReLL'23</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/worrell/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/worrell/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="workshop-on-reachability-recurrences-and-loops">Workshop On Reachability, Recurrences, and Loops&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="satellite-workshop-at-icalp-2023httpsicalp2023csupbde">Satellite Workshop at &lt;a href="https://icalp2023.cs.upb.de/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ICALP 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="heinz-nixdorf-museumsforum-hnf-seminar-room-5">Heinz Nixdorf MuseumsForum (HNF), Seminar Room 5&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="paderborn-germany">Paderborn, Germany&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="monday-10th-july-2023">Monday 10th July 2023&lt;/h4>
&lt;h4 id="workshop-registration-linkhttpsicalp2023csupbderegistration">&lt;a href="https://icalp2023.cs.upb.de/registration/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Workshop Registration Link&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="topic">Topic&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Recursively defined sequences are foundational objects of study in the computational sciences; they arise naturally in areas such as: the analysis of algorithms, weighted automata, loop termination, and probabilistic models.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="aim">Aim&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The aim of WORReLL'23 is to bring together researchers from the community and showcase cutting-edge research on the above topics.
The one-day workshop will also celebrate the research contributions of Professor James Worrell (also known as Ben). For context, Ben is giving an &lt;a href="https://icalp2023.cs.upb.de/invited-speakers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">invited talk&lt;/a> at ICALP this year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Coincidentally, the workshop is a few days prior to Ben&amp;rsquo;s birthday.
We plan to celebrate with a birthday dinner on Sunday 09th July (the evening before the workshop), so please take this into consideration for planning your travel to Paderborn.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure id="figure-professor-james-worrell">
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="Professor James Worrell" srcset="
/worrell/jbw_huf8e734c4952d304039a82f5706908e3d_19221_eada5ef6542e535558aa56cf078fc0f0.webp 400w,
/worrell/jbw_huf8e734c4952d304039a82f5706908e3d_19221_1c631d07bcd7f5cf20a3ad34cdc28ff3.webp 760w,
/worrell/jbw_huf8e734c4952d304039a82f5706908e3d_19221_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w"
src="https://georgekenison.github.io/worrell/jbw_huf8e734c4952d304039a82f5706908e3d_19221_eada5ef6542e535558aa56cf078fc0f0.webp"
width="310"
height="310"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;figcaption>
Professor James Worrell
&lt;/figcaption>&lt;/figure>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="participation">Participation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To participate in-person, please register for WORReLL'23 through ICALP&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://icalp2023.cs.upb.de/registration/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">registration portal&lt;/a>. To participate remotely over Zoom, please contact the organisers for further details.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="speakers-and-talks">Speakers and Talks&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>(Click on a talk title for the abstract.)&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="nikhil-balajihttpssitesgooglecomviewnikhilbalajihome-iit-delhi">&lt;a href="https://sites.google.com/view/nikhilbalaji/home" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nikhil Balaji&lt;/a> (IIT Delhi)&lt;/h4>
&lt;details class="spoiler " id="spoiler-1">
&lt;summary>&lt;em>On the Complexity of the Sum of Square Roots Problem&lt;/em>&lt;/summary>
&lt;p>Given positive integers $a_1, a_2, \dots, a_n$ and $b_1, b_2, \dots, b_m$, the Sum of Square Roots
problem (SSR) is the computational problem of checking if $\sqrt{a_1} + \sqrt{a_2} + \dots + \sqrt{a_n} &amp;gt; \sqrt{b_1} + \sqrt{b_2} + \dots + \sqrt{b_m}$.
It is an essential primitive in Computational Geometry where efficient algorithms for several geometric problems are known relative to SSR.
However the best-known complexity upper bound for SSR is in the Counting Hierarchy (CH), and no non-trivial lower bounds are known. Over the last two decades, SSR-hardness has emerged as a useful tool to capture the &amp;ldquo;numerical hardness&amp;rdquo; of problems, especially in Game Theory and Verification. In this talk, I will introduce a variant of SSR and show efficient &amp;ldquo;non-uniform&amp;rdquo; algorithms for this problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;/details>
&lt;h4 id="paul-bellhttpspcbellgithubio-keele">&lt;a href="https://pcbell.github.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Paul Bell&lt;/a> (Keele)&lt;/h4>
&lt;details class="spoiler " id="spoiler-2">
&lt;summary>&lt;em>From Quantum Automata to Quaternions and Rational Pairing Functions&lt;/em>&lt;/summary>
&lt;p>We investigate some recent results on injectivity for Quantum Finite Automata. We call a QFA injective if the acceptance probability of every input word is unique. We show the undecidability of this problem by using tools and results from linear algebra, quaternions, number theory, and in particular rational polynomial pairing functions. We note a huge disparity in the number of required states to show undecidability depending on whether the initial state vector is rational or real algebraic. We will draw parallels with interesting questions for other matrix theoretic problems, and introduce some new research directions and open problems.&lt;/p>
&lt;/details>
&lt;h4 id="dmitry-chistikovhttpswarwickacukfacscidcspeopledmitry_chistikov-warwick">&lt;a href="https://warwick.ac.uk/fac/sci/dcs/people/dmitry_chistikov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dmitry Chistikov&lt;/a> (Warwick)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Globe Hopping&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="valérie-berthéhttpswwwiriffrberthe-cnrs-paris">&lt;a href="https://www.irif.fr/~berthe/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Valérie Berthé&lt;/a> (CNRS, Paris)&lt;/h4>
&lt;details class="spoiler " id="spoiler-3">
&lt;summary>&lt;em>Recursive Sequences and Numeration&lt;/em>&lt;/summary>
&lt;p>In this lecture we revisit recursive sequences from the view point of numeration systems and their associated dynamical systems.
Linear recurrences allow indeed the definition of numerations for both integers and real numbers.
We focus on the so-called finiteness property which means that the set of elements having a finite expansion forms a ring, and on its numerous applications in arithmetics, aperiodic order, fractal geometry etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;/details>
&lt;h4 id="florian-lucahttpswwwwitsaczastaffacademic-a-z-listinglflorianlucawitsacza-witwatersrand">&lt;a href="https://www.wits.ac.za/staff/academic-a-z-listing/l/florianlucawitsacza/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Florian Luca&lt;/a> (Witwatersrand)&lt;/h4>
&lt;details class="spoiler " id="spoiler-4">
&lt;summary>&lt;em>Twisted Rational Zeros of Linearly Recurrent Sequences&lt;/em>&lt;/summary>
&lt;p>&lt;p>Let $( T_n )_{n} \in \mathbb{Z}$ be the Tribonacci numbers.
Marques and Lengyel (2014) obtained a formula relating the $2$-adic valuation of $T_n$ with the $2$-adic valuation of a linear function of $n$ (which might be constant) according to the residue class of $n$ modulo $32$ and optimistically conjectured that a similar formula holds true for every prime $p$.
In the first part of the talk, we will see that their conjecture was indeed far too optimistic; in particular, it fails for all but seven primes below $600$. Along the way, we are led to consider a certain twisted rational zero of a linearly recurrent sequence. We prove that non-degenerate linearly recurrent sequences have only finitely many such twisted rational zeros, which may be seen as an extension of the Skolem&amp;ndash;Mahler&amp;ndash;Lech theorem. While our method is, in general, not effective, in some cases we can compute all such twisted rational zeros. In particular, returning to the Tribonacci sequence we show that its only twisted rational zeros are the integral ones $-17,-4,-1,0$ together with the rational non-integral ones $1/3$ and $-5/3$.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is joint work with Y. Bilu, J. Nieuwveld, J. Ouaknine and J. Worrell.&lt;/p>
&lt;/p>
&lt;/details>
&lt;h4 id="joël-ouakninehttpspeoplempi-swsorgjoel-mpi-sws">&lt;a href="https://people.mpi-sws.org/~joel/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Joël Ouaknine&lt;/a> (MPI-SWS)&lt;/h4>
&lt;details class="spoiler " id="spoiler-5">
&lt;summary>&lt;em>Universal Skolem Sets&lt;/em>&lt;/summary>
&lt;p>&lt;p>The Skolem Problem asks to determine whether a given integer linear recurrence sequence (such as the Fibonacci numbers) has a zero term. This problem, whose decidability has been open for many decades, arises across a wide range of topics in computer science, including loop termination, probabilistic model checking, weighted automata theory, and dynamical systems, amongst many others. Recently, a new line of attack to the Skolem Problem was initiated via the notion of a Universal Skolem Set: a set S of positive integers such that it is decidable whether a given linear recurrence sequence has a zero in S. I will present an overview of this approach.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is joint work with Florian Luca, James Maynard, Armand Noubissie, and James Worrell.&lt;/p>
&lt;/p>
&lt;/details>
&lt;h4 id="veronika-pillweinhttpsriscjkuatmveronika-pillwein-jku">&lt;a href="https://risc.jku.at/m/veronika-pillwein/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Veronika Pillwein&lt;/a> (JKU)&lt;/h4>
&lt;details class="spoiler " id="spoiler-6">
&lt;summary>&lt;em>The Positivity Problem for Recurrent Sequences&lt;/em>&lt;/summary>
&lt;p>&lt;p>Proving positivity of sequences that are defined by recurrences is very
hard. Even when restricted to the seemingly simple class of sequences
defined by linear recurrences with constant coefficients (C-finite
sequences), decidability of the positivity problem is only known for
orders up to five.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, some computer algebra methods are able to tackle this
problem. Obviously, they do not succeed with all types of input and even
though correctness can be proven, termination is typically an issue. In
this talk, we will give an overview on this topic, present some
available methods and show cases where algorithmic proofs actually
succeeded.&lt;/p>
&lt;/p>
&lt;/details>
&lt;h4 id="igor-potapovhttpscgicsclivacukigorigor_potapovs_home_pagehomehtml-liverpool">&lt;a href="https://cgi.csc.liv.ac.uk/~igor/Igor_Potapovs_Home_Page/Home.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Igor Potapov&lt;/a> (Liverpool)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;em>tba&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="mahsa-shirmohammadihttpswwwiriffrmahsa-cnrs-paris">&lt;a href="https://www.irif.fr/~mahsa/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mahsa Shirmohammadi&lt;/a> (CNRS, Paris)&lt;/h4>
&lt;details class="spoiler " id="spoiler-7">
&lt;summary>&lt;em>The Membership Problem for Hypergeometric Sequences&lt;/em>&lt;/summary>
&lt;p>&lt;p>This talk is on the Membership problem for rational-valued
hypergeometric sequences. Such sequences $\langle u_n \rangle_{n=0}^{\infty}$
satisfies a first-order linear recurrence relation with polynomial
coefficients; that is, a recurrence of the form $f(n)u_n =
g(n)u_{n-1}$ where $f,g \in \mathbb{Z}[x]$.
The Membership Problem asks, given a hypergeometric sequence
$\langle u_n \rangle_{n=0}^{\infty}$ and a target value $t\in \mathbb{Q}$, determine whether
$t$ occurs in the sequence.
We give hints on recent decidability results of the Membership Problem
under the assumption that either (i) $f$ and $g$ have distinct
splitting fields, (ii) $f$ and $g$ split totally over
$\mathbb{Q}$, and (iii) $f$ and $g$ are monic polynomials that both
split over a quadratic extension of $\mathbb{Q}$.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This talk is based on two papers appearing in ISSAC'22 and ISSAC'23,
and are in collaboration with George Kenison, Amaury Pouly, Klara
Nosan, and James Worrell.&lt;/p>
&lt;/p>
&lt;/details>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="schedule">Schedule&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>09:00&amp;ndash;09:45 Valérie Berthé &lt;br>
09:45&amp;ndash;10:30 Dmitry Chistikov&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Coffee Break&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>11:00&amp;ndash;11:45 Mahsa Shirmohammadi &lt;br>
11:45&amp;ndash;12:30 Florian Luca&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Lunch&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>14:05&amp;ndash;14:25 Veronika Pillwein (Online) &lt;br>
14:25&amp;ndash;14:45 Nikhil Balaji &lt;br>
14:45&amp;ndash;15:30 Paul Bell&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Coffee Break&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>16:00&amp;ndash;16:45 Igor Potapov &lt;br>
16:45&amp;ndash;17:30 Joël Ouaknine&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Workshop Ends. ICALP food and drinks event begins.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="organisers">Organisers&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://georgekenison.github.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">George Kenison&lt;/a> (TU Wien)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.irif.fr/~mahsa/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mahsa Shirmohammadi&lt;/a> (CNRS, Paris)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="acknowledgements">Acknowledgements&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We gratefully acknowledge the financial support of both the CNRS and the ANR via the International Emerging Actions grant (IEA'22) and the VeSyAM grant (ANR-22-CE48-0005), respectively.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Orbit counting in conjugacy classes for free groups acting on trees</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2015-orbit/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2015-orbit/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/admin/config.yml</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/admin/config.yml</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>