<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Positivity Problem | George Kenison</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/tag/positivity-problem/</link><atom:link href="https://georgekenison.github.io/tag/positivity-problem/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Positivity Problem</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://georgekenison.github.io/media/icon_hu77e73f7cff5c696fd30270c2c33dd3bf_36783_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Positivity Problem</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/tag/positivity-problem/</link></image><item><title>Dynamical Systems and Program Analysis</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/post/dynamicaltalk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/post/dynamicaltalk/</guid><description>&lt;p>James (Ben) Worrell gave a keynote talk on algorithmic analysis of dynamical systems at the 48th ACM SIGPLAN Symposium on Principles of Programming Languages (POPL 2021).
During his talk, Ben presented some of our ongoing work on inequality decision problems for low-order holonomic sequences (&lt;a href="https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2020-positivity/">see here&lt;/a>). The abstract and recording for the talk are given below. Here are Ben&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://popl21.sigplan.org/details/POPL-2021-research-papers/69/Dynamical-Systems-and-Program-Analysis" target="_blank" rel="noopener">slides&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This talk is about the algorithmic analysis of dynamical systems and its relevance to the foundations of program analysis. A dynamical system is a state-based system that is specified by a rule specifying how the state changes over time (e.g., a swinging pendulum or a cobweb model of supply and demand in economics). While the study of dynamical systems permeates the quantitative sciences, in this talk we focus on computational aspects and their relevance to basic verification problems, such as termination and invariant synthesis. We highlight in particular certain problems that can be traced back to the program-analysis literature, e.g., concerning the decidability of termination for linear constraint loops and the computability of polyhedral and polynomial invariants for various classes of transition systems. In the talk we give some of the mathematical context of these problems, discuss recent progress, and highlight unsolved cases. The characteristic feature of the problems we consider is that they turn out to be much more challenging than they might first appear to the innocent-minded and in some cases have connections to problems at the frontiers of modern mathematics.&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9kUlHlvfU94" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>On minimality and positivity for second-order holonomic sequences</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/post/mfcstalk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/post/mfcstalk/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://georgekenison.github.io/files/202108MFCS.pdf" target="_blank">Slides&lt;/a>
on minimality and positivity for second-order holonomic sequences. Variations given at Mathematical Foundations of Computer Science 2021 (MFCS, Tallinn), the joint Forsyte (TU Wien) and Institute of Science &amp;amp; Technology Seminar, and the Open University Dynamical Systems Seminar.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>An infinite sequence $\langle u_n \rangle$ of real numbers is holonomic if it satisfies a linear recurrence relation with polynomial coefficients. Such a sequence is positive if each $u_n \geq 0$, and minimal if, given any other linearly independent sequence $\langle v_n \rangle$ satisfying the same recurrence relation, the ratio $u_n/v_n$ converges to $0$ as $n$ tends to infinity.
In recent work, the speaker and collaborators establish a Turing reduction of the problem of deciding positivity of second-order holonomic sequences to that of deciding minimality of such sequences. More specifically, we give a procedure for determining positivity of second-order holonomic sequences that terminates in all but an exceptional number of cases, and we show that in these exceptional cases positivity can be determined using an oracle for deciding minimality.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On Positivity and Minimality for Second-Order Holonomic Sequences</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2021-minimality/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2021-minimality/</guid><description/></item><item><title>On Inequality Decision Problems for Low-Order Holonomic Sequences</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2020-positivity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2020-positivity/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Holonomic techniques, periods, and decision problems</title><link>https://georgekenison.github.io/post/holonomictalk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://georgekenison.github.io/post/holonomictalk/</guid><description>&lt;p>Joël Ouaknine gave an invited talk on holonomic techniques, periods, and decision problems at Foundations of Software Technology and Theoretical Computer Science conference (FSTTCS 2020). During his talk Joël presented some of our ongoing work on inequality decision problems for low-order holonomic sequences (&lt;a href="https://georgekenison.github.io/publication/kenison-2020-positivity/">see here&lt;/a>). The abstract and recording for the talk are given below.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Holonomic techniques have deep roots going back to Wallis, Euler, and Gauss, and have evolved in modern times as an important subfield of computer algebra, thanks in large part to the work of Zeilberger and others over the past three decades. In this talk, I will give an overview of the area, and in particular will present a select survey of known and original results on decision problems for holonomic sequences and functions. I will also discuss some surprising connections to the theory of periods and exponential periods, which are classical objects of study in algebraic geometry and number theory; in particular, I will relate the decidability of certain decision problems for holonomic sequences to deep conjectures about periods and exponential periods, notably those due to Kontsevich and Zagier.&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/01j0OtQRjNk" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div></description></item></channel></rss>